No one knows how long humans have been giving themselves names, but one thing is sure: surnames are a much more recent idea than given names.
没人知道人类给自己取名字这件事已经有多久了，但有一件事是确定的：姓氏是一个比名字出现晚得多的概念。
In Europe, surnames were developed to distinguish between individuals who had the same moniker.
在欧洲，姓氏的产生是为了区分（distinguish）那些有相同名字（moniker）的人。
They were brought to the UK by the French nobility following the Norman Conquest around the 12th century and became common around the 14th century.
大约在12世纪诺曼征服之后，法国贵族将姓氏带到了英国，并在14世纪左右变得普遍起来。
Another tradition that the Normans introduced was that of coverture.
诺曼人引入的另一个传统是夫权制。
This was a law which said that a woman became a man's property when they got married.
这是一项法律，规定女人在结婚后就成为男人的财产。
In those days, only a man could be the head of the family and allowed to own property.
在那个时候，只有男人可以成为一家之主并被允许拥有财产。
At this point the bride lost her maiden name.
此时，新娘失去了她的娘家姓。
Over time, this has led to the tradition that upon marriage a woman relinquishes her maiden name and takes on her new husband’s family name.
随着时间的推移，这就形成了一种传统，即女人在结婚时会放弃（relinquishes）娘家姓，改用她新婚丈夫的姓氏。
Fast forward to the present.
快进到现在。
These days a woman choosing not to change her name to match her husband’s after marriage has long been a norm.
如今，女人在婚后选择不随丈夫姓早已成为一种常态。
The first recorded case is widely believed to be an American suffragette called Lucy Stone.
人们普遍认为，第一个有记录的案例是一位名叫露西・斯通（Lucy Stone）的美国妇女参政论者。
When she got married in 1855, she refused to take her husband's name.
1855年她结婚时，拒绝随丈夫姓。
After that, other ideas such as merging and double-barrelling also became common.
在那之后，其他的做法，比如合并姓氏（merging）和采用双姓（double-barrelling）也变得常见起来。
However, it would seem that a new trend is arising.
然而，似乎出现了一种新的趋势。
One in ten millennial males is now electing to replace their surname with their wife’s. That's according to a recent study of 2000 UK adults by Opinium, a strategic insight agency.
根据战略洞察机构奥皮尼姆（Opinium）最近对2000名英国成年人的一项研究，现在十分之一的千禧一代男性选择改用他们妻子的姓氏。
In a BBC article, Rory Dearlove née Cook, explained that for him it wasn’t important to keep his surname.
在BBC的一篇文章中，罗里・迪尔洛夫，原姓库克，解释道，对他来说，保留自己的姓氏并不重要。
He thought it would be nice for his wife and him to have the same last name.
他认为他和妻子有相同的姓氏会很好。
The bride, Lucy, had made it clear before getting married that she had no intention of changing hers, but thought that he would keep his too.
新娘露西在结婚前就明确表示她无意更改自己的姓氏，但她认为他也会保留自己的姓氏。
“He's entitled to keep his just as I am entitled to keep mine,” she commented.
“他有权保留他的姓氏，就像我有权保留我的一样，”她评论道。
Other men had different reasons.
其他男性有不同的原因。
Charlie Shaw, dubbed 'Morley' at birth, explained that it was, “a gesture of allegiance and an opportunity to acknowledge the unseen patriarchal bias and sexism in our society.”
查理・肖（Charlie Shaw），出生时被称为（dubbed）“莫利（Morley）”，他解释说，这是“一种表示忠诚（allegiance）的姿态，也是一个承认我们社会中无形的父权制（patriarchal）偏见和性别歧视（sexism）的机会。”
It’s worth noting that, in the UK at least, only the fathers of the couple being married are on the marriage certificate.
值得注意的是，至少在英国，结婚证上只有结婚双方的父亲的名字。
The mothers do not appear at all.
母亲的名字根本不会出现。
However, not everyone is in favour of altering tradition.
然而，并不是每个人都赞成改变传统。
Rachel Robnett, a researcher at the University of Nevada, surveyed a number of people in the US and UK and found that a man whose wife keeps her maiden name is viewed as ‘feminine’, while the woman was believed to ‘wear the trousers’.
内华达大学（University of Nevada）的研究员瑞秋・罗布内特（Rachel Robnett）对美国和英国的一些人进行了调查，发现妻子保留娘家姓的男人会被认为很“女性化”，而女人则被认为是“当家作主”。
And when one family found out that their son was to take his wife’s name, they refused to attend the wedding.
当一个家庭发现他们的儿子要改用妻子的姓氏时，他们拒绝参加婚礼。
To them it was proof that he was totally under the thumb.
对他们来说，这证明他受制于人（under the thumb）。
‘What’s in a name?’
“名字里包含着什么呢？”
Shakespeare asked in Romeo and Juliet.
莎士比亚在《罗密欧与朱丽叶》（Romeo and Juliet）中问道。
It would seem, depending on who you talk to, a great deal.
似乎，这取决于你和谁交谈，意义可能大不相同。
Whether maintaining traditional naming conventions, keeping the surname, or swapping names, these days at least there is a choice to be made.
无论是遵循传统的命名习俗，保留姓氏，还是交换姓氏，至少如今人们有了可以选择的机会。